nationalmeritscholarships.com 2011-05-07

# Privacy Policy - About Us - Scholarships.com

Scholarships.com recognizes that your privacy is important. To demonstrate our firm commitment to your privacy and to explain the types of information we obtain about visitors to our website, how that information is obtained and used, and how visitors can restrict its use or disclosure, we have created the Privacy Policy below. The following discusses our information gathering and dissemination practices at Scholarships.com. 

##  Information We Receive and How It Is Used

All personal information obtained by Scholarships.com about individual visitors to our website is information supplied voluntarily by that visitor. Our website's personal profile questionnaire requires users to volunteer contact information such as name and address, and demographic information such as age and income level. We ask if we may make that information available to our select list of marketing partners, which are reputable, leading companies and organizations that provide products and services of interest to students and parents. Our users choose whether to opt-in or opt-out of sharing their information with these partners. 

When Scholarships.com shares your personal information with a third party as described in this Privacy Policy, your personal information will become permanently subject to the information use and sharing practices of the third party. That third party will not be restricted by this Privacy Policy with respect to its use and further sharing of your personal information. If you agree to receive communications from our marketing partners and later change your mind, you may need to contact those companies directly. Any updates you wish to make to the information they possess must also be forwarded to the company communicating with you at that point in time. 

Users may make changes to the information in their personal profile at Scholarships.com at any time by logging-in to the website and entering the email address and password they submitted when creating their profile. After users have logged-in, they will be taken to their Scholarship Search Results. In the tabbed navigation at the top of the page, users will find a link to "Profile". By clicking on that tab, users will be taken to a summary of their information, divided into sections. An "Edit This Section" option in the upper-right corner of each section allows users to modify and update their information. To protect the security and integrity of users’ information, we will take reasonable steps to verify all new profile identities before providing access. It is the responsibility of the user to make all necessary changes in their profile to ensure the information they have provided while completing their registration or conducting a scholarship search remains current. 

Users of Scholarships.com who wish to terminate their membership at Scholarships.com may do so at any time by contacting our unsubscribe department. Please be sure to type "Remove" in the subject field and submit the email account associated with your profile, along with your password. 

Scholarships.com is committed to safeguarding users' privacy on our website. We require our employees to protect our users and visitors by keeping their profile information private, and expect our marketing partners to do the same. You can feel confident that your user profile will be protected when you visit Scholarships.com. We have security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of all user information under our control. 

##  Information Sharing & Email Preferences

Scholarships.com understands the importance of protecting personally-identifiable information. We will not share, sell, rent or otherwise transfer this information without the user's permission, and then only in accordance with the terms set forth in this Privacy Policy. Our website provides users the opportunity to unsubscribe (opt-out) from receiving email messages from Scholarships.com and its marketing partners, or from having their personal information shared with our marketing partners. Users may change their email preferences by clicking here. Users may also opt-in or opt-out entirely by clicking here. Please allow up to seven business days for these changes to take effect. 

We may communicate with our users through email to respond to visitors’ emails, to send information that a user has requested, or to inform users of new or updated scholarship awards and  financial aid opportunities. In the event a user contacts Scholarships.com directly via email, they will not be subject to receive any communication other than a response to that email such as promotional materials, unless the user specifically requests additional information. 

##  Collection of Passive Information

To gauge the effectiveness of our website, we collect generic information about our visitors that is not individually-identifiable. Our web servers automatically recognize a visitor's IP address, the web page from which a visitor enters our website, which pages a visitor visits, and how much time a visitor spends on each page. This information does not reveal a visitor's identity. We aggregate this information and use it to help diagnose problems with our web server, to administer to our website, or to evaluate and improve our website’s functions and resources. We use cookies to tell our server that a visitor has initiated a user session; however, they do not contain individually-identifiable information. Some of our business partners, such as advertisers, use cookies on our site, but we have no access to, nor control over, these cookies. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by Scholarships.com only and does not cover the use of cookies by our business partners. 

We may share statistical and demographic information about our website's visitors with our marketing partners. This information is only provided in the aggregate, meaning that the information is about our website's visitors as a group and not about individually-identifiable visitors. 

We follow generally-accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. However, no method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage is 100 percent secure. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially-acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. 

If you have any questions about security on our website, you can contact our privacy department.

##  Links to Other Websites

Scholarships.com contains text and banner links to other websites. Scholarships.com is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of those websites. 

##  Collection of Information from Children

In April 2000, the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) was passed to regulate the gathering of personal data online from children under the age of 13. Scholarships.com abides by COPPA, and works diligently to ensure compliance with the law. As such, Scholarships.com will not knowingly collect any personally-identifiable information from children under the age of 13, nor will children under the age of 13 be allowed to register with Scholarships.com. 

##  Notification of Changes

If we are going to use your personally identifiable information in a manner materially different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify you via email. You will have the option to decide whether we may use your information in this manner. In addition, if we make any material changes to our Privacy Policy that do not affect user information already stored in our database, we will post a prominent notice on our website notifying users of the change. In cases where we post notice of changes, we may also email users who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of those changes to our privacy practices. 

##  Testimonials

We post user testimonials on our website, all of which are volunteered and none of which contain individually-identifiable information beyond that user's first name, last initial, and photograph. Each user is made aware of the purpose of their supplied testimonial and the fact that it will be published at Scholarships.com. Users are under no obligation to participate, and we obtain the user's consent prior to posting this information.

##  TRUSTe Privacy Program

This Privacy Policy covers www.scholarships.com. The above TRUSTe trustmark confirms that Scholarships.com is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, nonprofit organization with a mission to build users' trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. Because Scholarships.com wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe. 

By displaying the TRUSTe trustmark, Scholarships.com has agreed to notify you of:

  * What personally-identifiable information of yours or third party personally identifiable information is collected from you through the web site
  * The organization collecting the information
  * How the information is used
  * With whom the information may be shared
  * What choices are available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of the information
  * The kind of security procedures that are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under control of Scholarships.com
  * How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information 

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact Scholarships.com's privacy department. If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or if your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe at http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php. TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with Scholarships.com to resolve your concerns. 

Scholarships.com has adopted privacy principles that state our commitment and define our policy on safeguarding visitor and user privacy when we conduct our business. Questions regarding this Privacy Policy statement, the practices of this website, or your dealings with Scholarships.com should be directed to Scholarships.com's privacy department. Alternatively, you may contact us at: 

Privacy at Scholarships.com   
Scholarships.com, LLC   
473 Central Avenue, Suite 6   
Highland Park, IL 60035
